<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>injured-workers on My Blog Site</title>
    <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/tags/injured-workers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in injured-workers on My Blog Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 15:00:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pemazomkyi.com/tags/injured-workers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Workers&#39; Comp Is A Right! - December 10, 2018 at 11:30am</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/workers-comp-is-a-right-december-10-2018-at-11-30am/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 15:00:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/workers-comp-is-a-right-december-10-2018-at-11-30am/</guid>
      <description>Workers’ Comp is a Right! Join us for a province-wide week of action from December 10th to the 14th, and take a stand for fairness for injured workers!
 In Toronto, we’re kicking the week off with a rally on Monday, December 10th at 11:30am outside the Ministry of Labour located at 400 University Avenue - view map for directions.
Click here to access a PDF of the 2018 Toronto Rally Poster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injured Workers&#39; Demonstration - December 11, 2017 at 11:30am</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/injured-workers-demonstration-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 09:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/injured-workers-demonstration-1/</guid>
      <description>All We Want for Christmas is Fair Workers’ Comp! Injured Workers&amp;rsquo; Holiday Outreach Blitz.  Toronto:
Meet at 11:30am at Yonge &amp;amp; Dundas Square [Map]
Contact workerscompisaright@gmail.com for more information or visit the Facebook event page.
 On Monday December 11th, join us in communities across the province, to celebrate the strength and resilience of injured workers who refuse to back down from the struggle for fair compensation.
The holiday season can be a difficult time for injured workers who have been forced into poverty because of the Workplace Safety and Insurance Board&amp;rsquo;s focus on saving its own money by slashing compensation benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual Report 2017</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/annual-report-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 08:04:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/annual-report-2017/</guid>
      <description>The Workers&amp;rsquo; Health and Safety Legal Clinic’s Annual Report outlines the activities and initiatives that were made in pursuit of advocating for workers’ rights. It further details the Clinic’s efforts to continue providing consistently high quality services in a cost-effective, efficient and innovative manner. The Clinic provides such legal services as advice, representation, public legal education and law reform concerning occupational health and safety and related workplace laws.
 The following PDF documents are available for review -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Summer 2017 Newsletter – Vol. 25, No. 2</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/-summer-2017-newsletter-vol.-25-no.-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/-summer-2017-newsletter-vol.-25-no.-2/</guid>
      <description>The Workers’ Health and Safety Legal Clinic is pleased to publish its Summer 2017 Newsletter – Vol. 25, No. 2.
In this publication, you will find commentary about clinic casework and law reform efforts, as well as meet our new staff.
 Read more on these issues in the Summer 2017 Clinic Newsletter.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>¡Buena Paga! --- Voces Latinas 1610AM - Sábado 10 de junio de 2017 a las 3:00 pm</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/buena-paga-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 11:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/buena-paga-1/</guid>
      <description>El tema de esta semana:
Accidentes en el lugar de trabajo - Cómo reportarlos a WSIB. El sábado 10 de junio a las 3:00 pm, Julio Díaz discutirá cómo reportar un accidente en el lugar de trabajo a la Compensación (&amp;ldquo;WSIB&amp;rdquo;). Durante el show, los oyentes y las oyentes aprenderán a reportar una enfermedad o lesión en el trabajo, qué deben decir cuando reciben atención médica por una lesión y qué pasos se deben tomar para presentar una reclamación de compensación de trabajadores con el WSIB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injured Workers’ Day - June 1st, 2017 at 11:30am, Queen’s Park</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/injured-workers-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 12:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/injured-workers-day/</guid>
      <description>Workers&amp;rsquo; Compensation is a Right! Injured Workers&amp;rsquo; Day Rally and March. Despite the epidemic of precarious, unsafe, and toxic work, the Workplace Safety and Insurance Board (WSIB) is more concerned with its own bottom line than with protecting the well-being of injured workers in Ontario.
We need to come together and demand our right to workers&amp;rsquo; compensation.
Join us on the streets!
June 1st , 2017 &amp;mdash; 11:30am - at Queen’s Park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>¡Buena Paga! --- Voces Latinas 1610AM - Sábados a las 3:00pm</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/buena-paga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 15:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/buena-paga/</guid>
      <description>A partir del sábado 3 de junio a las 3:00pm, Julio Díaz conducirá un programa semanal de radio sobre los problemas en el trabajo que afectan a los trabajadores indocumentados de habla hispana.
Cada semana habrá un nuevo tema e invitados especiales. También se presentarán escenarios de problemas en el trabajo y se contestarán llamadas de los oyentes, quienes traerán sus propias experiencias y conocimientos a la discusión.
Sintoniza en Voces Latinas – 1610AM cada sábado de 3:00pm a 4:00pm para discutir diferentes problemas en el lugar de trabajo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day of Mourning - Italian Fallen Workers Memorial - April 28th at 3:00 pm</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/day-of-mourning-italian-fallen-workers-memorial-april-28th-at-3-00-pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 17:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/day-of-mourning-italian-fallen-workers-memorial-april-28th-at-3-00-pm/</guid>
      <description>Last year, on April 28, the Committee for the Italian Fallen Workers Memorial Project was proud to formally unveil the Italian Fallen Workers Memorial Wall honouring almost one thousand workers of Italian origin who have been killed in workplace tragedies across Ontario.
This year, the Committee will be adding hundreds of names and broadening the project to include workers of Italian origin who were killed in these terrible workplace tragedies across Canada, from 1900 to today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injured Workers&#39; Demonstration</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/injured-workers-demonstration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 09:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/injured-workers-demonstration/</guid>
      <description>Injured workers, advocates, union members and allies rallied in Toronto on December 12th, for the annual call to action against austerity measures that have been taken by the Workers Safety and Insurance Board (WSIB).
  The rally began at the WSIB’s Toronto office located at 200 Front Street West and then continued at the Ombudsman’s office located at 483 Bay Street. A letter voicing concerns with the WSIB was delivered to a representative of Ontario’s Ombudsman, Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>