<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Newsletter on My Blog Site</title>
    <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/categories/newsletter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Newsletter on My Blog Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pemazomkyi.com/categories/newsletter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title> Summer 2017 Newsletter – Vol. 25, No. 2</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/-summer-2017-newsletter-vol.-25-no.-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/-summer-2017-newsletter-vol.-25-no.-2/</guid>
      <description>The Workers’ Health and Safety Legal Clinic is pleased to publish its Summer 2017 Newsletter – Vol. 25, No. 2.
In this publication, you will find commentary about clinic casework and law reform efforts, as well as meet our new staff.
 Read more on these issues in the Summer 2017 Clinic Newsletter.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring 2017 Newsletter – Vol. 25, No. 1</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/spring-2017-newsletter-vol-25-issue-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 14:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/spring-2017-newsletter-vol-25-issue-1/</guid>
      <description>The Workers’ Health and Safety Legal Clinic is pleased to publish its Spring 2017 Newsletter – Vol. 25, No. 1.
In this publication, you will find commentary about clinic casework and law reform efforts, as well as meet our new staff.
Read more on these issues in the Spring 2017 Clinic Newsletter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radon Hazards</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/newsletter-2016-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 20:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/newsletter-2016-08/</guid>
      <description>U of T Engineering Students’ proposal for Ontario Building Code changes for Radon Gas. According to the World Health Organization, radon gas has become the second leading cause of lung cancer. In Ontario, high levels of radon can be found within Toronto’s GTA. Since there are no legal requirements in Ontario for radon testing, the currentOntario Building Code is inadequate to handle radon as a rising problem.The Canadian Environmental Law Association issued a report in November 2014 called Radon in Homes, Schools, and Workplaces: CELA Finds Legal Protections Lacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operation Rainbow</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/operation-rainbow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 21:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/operation-rainbow/</guid>
      <description>U of T Engineering Students’ proposals to safely replace the dangerous high school Rainbow Experiment. Our Clinic continued its partnership with first year engineering students at the University of Toronto participating in U of T Engineering Strategies &amp;amp; Practice Course, and the Multidisciplinary Capstone Design Course.Proposed by Clinic volunteer, Dr. Michael Grossman, “Operation Rainbow” is a project that seeks to resolve the safety problems surrounding the Rainbow Experiment: a laboratory experiment performed in secondary schools that identify characteristic colours produced by crystalline compounds when ignited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kazenelson Case</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/newsletter-2016-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/newsletter-2016-02/</guid>
      <description>Criminal Code – Prison Sentence: The effect of the Kazenelson criminal law decision on legal advice to workers. In concluding a case commentary in the previous issue of this newsletter, I asked: &amp;ldquo;Has Kazenelson changed the rules of engagement for going to work? Should workers worry about this?&amp;rdquo;
In this polemic, I try to explain why my answers are: yes &amp;amp; yes.
The Kazenelson case is the first major conviction under the Westray-changed Criminal Code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>