<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>undocumented-workers on My Blog Site</title>
    <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/tags/undocumented-workers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in undocumented-workers on My Blog Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 08:04:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pemazomkyi.com/tags/undocumented-workers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual Report 2017</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/annual-report-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 08:04:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/annual-report-2017/</guid>
      <description>The Workers&amp;rsquo; Health and Safety Legal Clinic’s Annual Report outlines the activities and initiatives that were made in pursuit of advocating for workers’ rights. It further details the Clinic’s efforts to continue providing consistently high quality services in a cost-effective, efficient and innovative manner. The Clinic provides such legal services as advice, representation, public legal education and law reform concerning occupational health and safety and related workplace laws.
 The following PDF documents are available for review -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Summer 2017 Newsletter – Vol. 25, No. 2</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/-summer-2017-newsletter-vol.-25-no.-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/-summer-2017-newsletter-vol.-25-no.-2/</guid>
      <description>The Workers’ Health and Safety Legal Clinic is pleased to publish its Summer 2017 Newsletter – Vol. 25, No. 2.
In this publication, you will find commentary about clinic casework and law reform efforts, as well as meet our new staff.
 Read more on these issues in the Summer 2017 Clinic Newsletter.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>¡Buena Paga! --- Voces Latinas 1610AM - Sábado 10 de junio de 2017 a las 3:00 pm</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/buena-paga-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 11:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/buena-paga-1/</guid>
      <description>El tema de esta semana:
Accidentes en el lugar de trabajo - Cómo reportarlos a WSIB. El sábado 10 de junio a las 3:00 pm, Julio Díaz discutirá cómo reportar un accidente en el lugar de trabajo a la Compensación (&amp;ldquo;WSIB&amp;rdquo;). Durante el show, los oyentes y las oyentes aprenderán a reportar una enfermedad o lesión en el trabajo, qué deben decir cuando reciben atención médica por una lesión y qué pasos se deben tomar para presentar una reclamación de compensación de trabajadores con el WSIB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>¡Buena Paga! --- Voces Latinas 1610AM - Sábados a las 3:00pm</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/buena-paga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 15:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/buena-paga/</guid>
      <description>A partir del sábado 3 de junio a las 3:00pm, Julio Díaz conducirá un programa semanal de radio sobre los problemas en el trabajo que afectan a los trabajadores indocumentados de habla hispana.
Cada semana habrá un nuevo tema e invitados especiales. También se presentarán escenarios de problemas en el trabajo y se contestarán llamadas de los oyentes, quienes traerán sus propias experiencias y conocimientos a la discusión.
Sintoniza en Voces Latinas – 1610AM cada sábado de 3:00pm a 4:00pm para discutir diferentes problemas en el lugar de trabajo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>