<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Blog Site</title>
    <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My Blog Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 15:00:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pemazomkyi.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Workers&#39; Comp Is A Right! - December 10, 2018 at 11:30am</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/workers-comp-is-a-right-december-10-2018-at-11-30am/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 15:00:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/workers-comp-is-a-right-december-10-2018-at-11-30am/</guid>
      <description>Workers’ Comp is a Right! Join us for a province-wide week of action from December 10th to the 14th, and take a stand for fairness for injured workers!
 In Toronto, we’re kicking the week off with a rally on Monday, December 10th at 11:30am outside the Ministry of Labour located at 400 University Avenue - view map for directions.
Click here to access a PDF of the 2018 Toronto Rally Poster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PTSD Prevention</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/ptsd-prevention-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/ptsd-prevention-1/</guid>
      <description>The rate of workplace fatalities and critical injuries in Ontario workplaces have worsened in recent years.
The Occupational Health And Safety Act (OHSA) requires that all traumatic accidents where fatalities and critical injuries occur in the workplace must be investigated by elected members of a Joint Health and Safety Committee, or a health and safety representative. More often than not, this process will likely require an extended involvement in a protracted investigation potentially involving the Ministry of Labour, the Police, and the Coroner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual Report 2018</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/annual-report-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 10:28:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/annual-report-2018/</guid>
      <description>The Workers&amp;rsquo; Health and Safety Legal Clinic’s Annual Report outlines the activities and initiatives that were made in pursuit of advocating for workers’ rights.
It further details the Clinic’s efforts to continue providing consistently high quality services in a cost-effective, efficient and innovative manner.
The Clinic provides such legal services as advice, representation, public legal education and law reform concerning occupational health and safety and related workplace laws.
 The following PDF documents are available for review -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGM - October 24, 2018 at 6:00pm</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/agm-october-24-2018-at-600pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 16:52:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/agm-october-24-2018-at-600pm/</guid>
      <description>The Workers&amp;rsquo; Health and Safety Legal Clinic will be hosting its Annual General Meeting on Wednesday, October 24th, 2018 at 6:00 pm.
Join us at 180 Dundas Street West, 19th Floor, Toronto, Ontario, M5G 1Z8. We are located east of University Avenue [map].
Light refreshments will be served.
 Click here to access a .PDF version of the AGM Agenda.
Click here to access a .PDF version of our 2018 Annual Report and Audited Financial Statements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workers&#39; Guide</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/workers-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 10:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/workers-guide/</guid>
      <description>Protect your health and safety! As a worker in Ontario, you have basic health and safety rights. It is against the law for your boss to fire you or punish you (or threaten to fire or punish you) for using your health and safety rights.
 Click below to learn more:
WORKERS’ GUIDE TO OCCUPATIONAL HEALTH AND SAFETY.  For more information on our services or if you have have been fired or punished for speaking out about your rights, contact us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injured Workers&#39; Demonstration - December 11, 2017 at 11:30am</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/injured-workers-demonstration-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 09:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/injured-workers-demonstration-1/</guid>
      <description>All We Want for Christmas is Fair Workers’ Comp! Injured Workers&amp;rsquo; Holiday Outreach Blitz.  Toronto:
Meet at 11:30am at Yonge &amp;amp; Dundas Square [Map]
Contact workerscompisaright@gmail.com for more information or visit the Facebook event page.
 On Monday December 11th, join us in communities across the province, to celebrate the strength and resilience of injured workers who refuse to back down from the struggle for fair compensation.
The holiday season can be a difficult time for injured workers who have been forced into poverty because of the Workplace Safety and Insurance Board&amp;rsquo;s focus on saving its own money by slashing compensation benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual Report 2017</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/annual-report-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 08:04:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/annual-report-2017/</guid>
      <description>The Workers&amp;rsquo; Health and Safety Legal Clinic’s Annual Report outlines the activities and initiatives that were made in pursuit of advocating for workers’ rights. It further details the Clinic’s efforts to continue providing consistently high quality services in a cost-effective, efficient and innovative manner. The Clinic provides such legal services as advice, representation, public legal education and law reform concerning occupational health and safety and related workplace laws.
 The following PDF documents are available for review -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Initiatives</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 15:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/project/</guid>
      <description>Undocumented workers in Ontario are more likely to take physically demanding jobs for less than minimum wage, and are more often exposed to hazards that cause accidents and injuries.
Since early spring, we have participated in numerous demonstrations, cultural events and community fairs, and we have outreached through workshops and presentations.
We are pleased to announce two interactive initiatives that have been created to further connect with the Spanish-speaking community:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Summer 2017 Newsletter – Vol. 25, No. 2</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/-summer-2017-newsletter-vol.-25-no.-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/-summer-2017-newsletter-vol.-25-no.-2/</guid>
      <description>The Workers’ Health and Safety Legal Clinic is pleased to publish its Summer 2017 Newsletter – Vol. 25, No. 2.
In this publication, you will find commentary about clinic casework and law reform efforts, as well as meet our new staff.
 Read more on these issues in the Summer 2017 Clinic Newsletter.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staff</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/menu/aboutus/staff/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 17:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/menu/aboutus/staff/</guid>
      <description>The Workers&amp;rsquo; Health and Safety Legal Clinic (WHSLC) employs four lawyers and two community legal workers. We offer articling opportunities when funding is available, and law student volunteer positions are possible where oversight is available.
Go back </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>¡Buena Paga! --- Voces Latinas 1610AM - Sábado 10 de junio de 2017 a las 3:00 pm</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/buena-paga-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 11:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/buena-paga-1/</guid>
      <description>El tema de esta semana:
Accidentes en el lugar de trabajo - Cómo reportarlos a WSIB. El sábado 10 de junio a las 3:00 pm, Julio Díaz discutirá cómo reportar un accidente en el lugar de trabajo a la Compensación (&amp;ldquo;WSIB&amp;rdquo;). Durante el show, los oyentes y las oyentes aprenderán a reportar una enfermedad o lesión en el trabajo, qué deben decir cuando reciben atención médica por una lesión y qué pasos se deben tomar para presentar una reclamación de compensación de trabajadores con el WSIB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injured Workers’ Day - June 1st, 2017 at 11:30am, Queen’s Park</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/injured-workers-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 12:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/injured-workers-day/</guid>
      <description>Workers&amp;rsquo; Compensation is a Right! Injured Workers&amp;rsquo; Day Rally and March. Despite the epidemic of precarious, unsafe, and toxic work, the Workplace Safety and Insurance Board (WSIB) is more concerned with its own bottom line than with protecting the well-being of injured workers in Ontario.
We need to come together and demand our right to workers&amp;rsquo; compensation.
Join us on the streets!
June 1st , 2017 &amp;mdash; 11:30am - at Queen’s Park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>¡Buena Paga! --- Voces Latinas 1610AM - Sábados a las 3:00pm</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/buena-paga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 15:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/buena-paga/</guid>
      <description>A partir del sábado 3 de junio a las 3:00pm, Julio Díaz conducirá un programa semanal de radio sobre los problemas en el trabajo que afectan a los trabajadores indocumentados de habla hispana.
Cada semana habrá un nuevo tema e invitados especiales. También se presentarán escenarios de problemas en el trabajo y se contestarán llamadas de los oyentes, quienes traerán sus propias experiencias y conocimientos a la discusión.
Sintoniza en Voces Latinas – 1610AM cada sábado de 3:00pm a 4:00pm para discutir diferentes problemas en el lugar de trabajo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trabajadores Indocumentados / Undocumented Workers</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/undocumented-workers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 11:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/undocumented-workers/</guid>
      <description>Projecto de Ayuda a Trabajadores Indocumentados con Problemas de Salud y Seguridad en el Trabajo Preventing Injuries amongst Undocumented Workers Click here to access the English version of this web page.
Click the below links to access for our booklets in English and Spanish:
WORKERS&amp;rsquo; GUIDE TO OCCUPATIONAL HEALTH AND SAFETY TU SALUD Y SEGURIDAD EN EL TRABAJO: Información para Trabajadores  Todos y todas necesitamos protección en el trabajo independientemente de nuestro estatus en Canadá.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/menu/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 19:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/menu/contact/</guid>
      <description>The Workers’ Health and Safety Legal Clinic provides free legal services to non-unionized workers in the province of Ontario who are experiencing health and safety and/or employment related legal issues in the workplace.
Feel free to contact us by phone or email for information, to receive our services, to become a member, to join the Board of Directors, or to inquire about volunteer opportunities.   Telephone: 416-971-8832 (Local) or 1-877-832-6090 (Toll free)   Fax: 416-971-8834   Email: whslc@lao.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring 2017 Newsletter – Vol. 25, No. 1</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/spring-2017-newsletter-vol-25-issue-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 14:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/spring-2017-newsletter-vol-25-issue-1/</guid>
      <description>The Workers’ Health and Safety Legal Clinic is pleased to publish its Spring 2017 Newsletter – Vol. 25, No. 1.
In this publication, you will find commentary about clinic casework and law reform efforts, as well as meet our new staff.
Read more on these issues in the Spring 2017 Clinic Newsletter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day of Mourning - Italian Fallen Workers Memorial - April 28th at 3:00 pm</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/day-of-mourning-italian-fallen-workers-memorial-april-28th-at-3-00-pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 17:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/day-of-mourning-italian-fallen-workers-memorial-april-28th-at-3-00-pm/</guid>
      <description>Last year, on April 28, the Committee for the Italian Fallen Workers Memorial Project was proud to formally unveil the Italian Fallen Workers Memorial Wall honouring almost one thousand workers of Italian origin who have been killed in workplace tragedies across Ontario.
This year, the Committee will be adding hundreds of names and broadening the project to include workers of Italian origin who were killed in these terrible workplace tragedies across Canada, from 1900 to today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injured Workers&#39; Demonstration</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/injured-workers-demonstration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 09:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/injured-workers-demonstration/</guid>
      <description>Injured workers, advocates, union members and allies rallied in Toronto on December 12th, for the annual call to action against austerity measures that have been taken by the Workers Safety and Insurance Board (WSIB).
  The rally began at the WSIB’s Toronto office located at 200 Front Street West and then continued at the Ombudsman’s office located at 483 Bay Street. A letter voicing concerns with the WSIB was delivered to a representative of Ontario’s Ombudsman, Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newsletters</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/newsletters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 15:43:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/newsletters/</guid>
      <description>The Workers&amp;rsquo; Health and Safety Legal Clinic&amp;rsquo;s newsletters feature commentary on case law and legislative reform, highlight ongoing clinic activities, special projects as well as recent workplace health and safety news.
Scroll down to access the Clinic&amp;rsquo;s newsletters dating back to 2010.
Spring 2017 - Issue: Vol. 25, No. 1
IN THIS ISSUE &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; Case Report: All Parties are Equal before the Human Rights Tribunal / Law Reform – Workers’ Rights in Focus: The Changing Workplaces Review / Clinic Update – New Website Launch: www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual Report 2016</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/annual-report-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 12:30:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/annual-report-2016/</guid>
      <description>The Workers&amp;rsquo; Health and Safety Legal Clinic’s Annual Report outlines the activities and initiatives that were made in pursuit of advocating for workers’ rights. It further details the Clinic’s efforts to continue providing consistently high quality services in a cost-effective, efficient and innovative manner. The Clinic provides such legal services as advice, representation, public legal education and law reform concerning occupational health and safety and related workplace laws.
 The following PDF documents are available for review -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinic History</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/menu/aboutus/clinic-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 20:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/menu/aboutus/clinic-history/</guid>
      <description>The Toronto Workers’ Health and Safety Legal Clinic began operations in December 1988. The Clinic was founded by a group of health and safety advocates who originally were part of the Toronto Occupational Health Resource Centre (TOHRC). TOHRC was set up in the 1970s to assist non-unionized workers in dealing with occupational health and safety hazards.
When the Occupational Health and Safety Act came into being in 1978, TOHRC recognized that non-union workers needed legal help to assert their health and safety rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Law Reform</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/law-reform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 20:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/law-reform/</guid>
      <description>The Workers’ Health and Safety Legal Clinic (WHSLC) participates in law reform and community development activities that benefit or assist low wage non-unionized workers in Ontario.
Law reform is an important component to WHSLC activities. We engage in networking with like-minded organizations, and we participate in a variety of law reform and community development initiatives that seek to make systematic changes to the laws and policies governing employment, health and safety, workers&amp;rsquo; compensation and related workplace laws.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archives</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 20:05:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/archives/</guid>
      <description>The following archives include a diverse collection of Clinic newsletters, print materials, Annual Reports and other historical documentation.
 Please note: Some of the archived Clinic newsletters contain within them links to documents that may no longer be available. To inquire further, contact us.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/menu/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 16:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/menu/links/</guid>
      <description>In this section, you will find information on a variety of issues that relate to workers&amp;rsquo; employment standards and health and safety rights. Scroll down and click on the highlighted text to access the links.
 LEGAL ASSISTANCE RESOURCES Legal Aid Ontario (LAO) – provides free legal services to low-income people in Ontario. LAO seeks to ensure that healthy communities include legal services and access to justice.
  Tel (416) 979-1446 / Toll free 1-800-668-8258</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outreach</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/public-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 16:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/public-education/</guid>
      <description>Public Legal Education The Workers&amp;rsquo; Health and Safety Legal Clinic (WHSLC) has developed a strong focus on public legal education by way of oral presentations and workshops to community agencies, schools, job connection programs, apprenticeship programs and employment readiness programs such as Enhanced Language Training.
Our Community Legal Workers travel all over the City of Toronto and the Greater Toronto Area to inform youth, job seekers and newcomers about employment rights as well as health and safety rights at work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legal Services</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/legal-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 14:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/legal-services/</guid>
      <description>What We Do The Workers&amp;rsquo; Health and Safety Legal Clinic (WHSLC) provides legal services to low-income non-unionized workers who need assistance with legal matters that relate to their employment rights or their health and safety rights at work. Our legal services include summary legal advice, brief legal services, referrals, and legal representation.
Your privacy is very important to us. The WHSLC follows the Law Society of Upper Canada&amp;rsquo;s rules regarding client confidentiality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radon Hazards</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/newsletter-2016-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 20:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/newsletter-2016-08/</guid>
      <description>U of T Engineering Students’ proposal for Ontario Building Code changes for Radon Gas. According to the World Health Organization, radon gas has become the second leading cause of lung cancer. In Ontario, high levels of radon can be found within Toronto’s GTA. Since there are no legal requirements in Ontario for radon testing, the currentOntario Building Code is inadequate to handle radon as a rising problem.The Canadian Environmental Law Association issued a report in November 2014 called Radon in Homes, Schools, and Workplaces: CELA Finds Legal Protections Lacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operation Rainbow</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/operation-rainbow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 21:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/operation-rainbow/</guid>
      <description>U of T Engineering Students’ proposals to safely replace the dangerous high school Rainbow Experiment. Our Clinic continued its partnership with first year engineering students at the University of Toronto participating in U of T Engineering Strategies &amp;amp; Practice Course, and the Multidisciplinary Capstone Design Course.Proposed by Clinic volunteer, Dr. Michael Grossman, “Operation Rainbow” is a project that seeks to resolve the safety problems surrounding the Rainbow Experiment: a laboratory experiment performed in secondary schools that identify characteristic colours produced by crystalline compounds when ignited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kazenelson Case</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/newsletter-2016-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/communications/newsletter-2016-02/</guid>
      <description>Criminal Code – Prison Sentence: The effect of the Kazenelson criminal law decision on legal advice to workers. In concluding a case commentary in the previous issue of this newsletter, I asked: &amp;ldquo;Has Kazenelson changed the rules of engagement for going to work? Should workers worry about this?&amp;rdquo;
In this polemic, I try to explain why my answers are: yes &amp;amp; yes.
The Kazenelson case is the first major conviction under the Westray-changed Criminal Code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/menu/about-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/menu/about-us/</guid>
      <description>Who We Are The Workers’ Health and Safety Legal Clinic (WHSLC) is a community legal aid clinic that focuses on workers’ rights with an emphasis on workplace health and safety issues and employment law issues.
Our lawyers provide free information, legal advice, referrals and representation to low-income workers who face health and safety problems at work and/or other violations of their rights. We act for workers to promote health and safety in the workplace, and in particular, for those who are unlawfully punished or terminated for raising health and safety concerns and/or employment related concerns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Board of Directors</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/menu/aboutus/board-of-directors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/menu/aboutus/board-of-directors/</guid>
      <description>The Workers&amp;rsquo; Health and Safety Legal Clinic (WHSLC) is governed by a volunteer Board of Directors elected by our membership. Our Board members come from a variety of backgrounds and share a common interest in employment-related and health and safety issues from the worker perspective. Currently, many of our Board members have had experience with health and safety issues at work or were injured in the workplace.
Being a volunteer Board member is an opportunity to network, to meet others who share your commitment, and to enrich your own skills, knowledge and experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canada Labour Code</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/dismissals/canada-labor-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/dismissals/canada-labor-code/</guid>
      <description>Unjust Dismissals We represent workers who were employed in federally regulated workplaces (such as banks, telecommunications, inter-provincial transportation) and dismissed in a manner that does not comply with the Canada Labour Code (CLC). The CLC contains unjust dismissal provisions that apply to non-managerial workers employed for 12 months (1 year) or more who are dismissed without just cause. We also represent workers in federally regulated workplaces that have been punished or fired for raising an occupational health and safety issue or concern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employment Standards</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/dismissals/employment-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/dismissals/employment-standards/</guid>
      <description>Reprisals It is against the law for an employer or agency to punish or terminate workers for enforcing or trying to enforce the rights found under the Employment Standards Act (ESA). These rights include the right to receive minimum wage, overtime pay, pay stubs, sick leave, parental leave, termination pay, vacation pay, and much more.
WHSLC lawyers are available to appear at the Ontario Labour Relations Board to represent workers who have been disciplined/fired for exercising or trying to exercise their rights under the ESA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health and Safety Reprisals</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/dismissals/hsreprisals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/dismissals/hsreprisals/</guid>
      <description>The core of our Clinic&amp;rsquo;s mandate is to represent workers who are disciplined or fired for raising health and safety concerns at work. Some common health and safety concerns are unsafe working conditions, workplace harassment, workplace violence, poor ventilation or exposure to chemical hazards. These are just a few of the health and safety concerns that can arise in any workplace.
WHSLC lawyers are experienced in advocacy before the Ontario Labour Relations Board and in seeking remedies such as lost wages, general damages, and reinstatement to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Rights Applications</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/dismissals/human-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/dismissals/human-rights/</guid>
      <description>Employment and Disability We represent workers who are dismissed from work because of a disability or because they asked for accommodation or a change in work duties due to a disability. We have acted for workers who lose their jobs simply for having an injury at work for which Workplace Safety and Insurance Board (WSIB) benefits were claimed.
 Go back </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Membership</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/menu/member/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/menu/member/</guid>
      <description>Become a Member! The WHSLC is supported by a diverse membership. Our primary goal is to provide free legal services to non-unionized workers experiencing employment issues and/or health and safety legal issues in Ontario. To help us ensure that our services are relevant, we need the participation of people experiencing workplace injustices in Ontario, as well as those who are serving vulnerable workers who experience unfair workplace practices.
Please consider becoming a member and sharing your voice in the fight for improved health and safety as well as employment standards in Ontario’s workplaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Claims Court</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/dismissals/small-claims/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/dismissals/small-claims/</guid>
      <description>Wrongful Dismissal and Constructive Dismissal Lawsuits We file lawsuits against employers and represent workers who are wrongfully dismissed or laid off without proper notice or pay in lieu (instead) of notice.
Additionally, if there is a fundamental change to working conditions that leave a worker with no option but to quit, we can represent workers in a lawsuit against the employer based on constructive dismissal.
 Go back </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlawful Dismissals</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/unlawful-dismissals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/unlawful-dismissals/</guid>
      <description>The Workers&amp;rsquo; Health and Safety Legal Clinic provides advice and representation on a number of unlawful dismissal matters including:
 Health and Safety Reprisals Employment Standards: Reprisals and Termination Pay/Severance Pay Claims Human Rights Applications Canada Labour Code: Unjust Dismissals and Reprisals Small Claims Court: Wrongful Dismissal and Constructive Dismissal Lawsuits   Go back </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who We Serve</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/menu/who-we-serve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/menu/who-we-serve/</guid>
      <description>Financial Eligibility Our services are available, free of charge, to low-income non-unionized workers who need assistance with legal matters that fall within the Clinic’s area of practice. For more information on our areas of practice, visit the Legal Services section on our website. We use Legal Aid Ontario’s financial eligibility criteria to determine if you are eligible for services from our Clinic. This eligibility is based on household size and income.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workplace Safety and Insurance Board</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/workplace-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/workplace-safety/</guid>
      <description>Workers covered by Workplace Safety and Insurance Act have the right to claim benefits from the Workplace Safety and Insurance Board (WSIB). Benefits can include loss of earnings benefits (also known as workers’ compensation) or healthcare coverage. The WSIB also assists with return to work and retraining. We provide advice for all WSIB issues but representation only in specific types of claim issues like Work Transition Services appeals as well as Occupational Disease appeals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>