<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Features on My Blog Site</title>
    <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Features on My Blog Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pemazomkyi.com/features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PTSD Prevention</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/ptsd-prevention-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/ptsd-prevention-1/</guid>
      <description>The rate of workplace fatalities and critical injuries in Ontario workplaces have worsened in recent years.
The Occupational Health And Safety Act (OHSA) requires that all traumatic accidents where fatalities and critical injuries occur in the workplace must be investigated by elected members of a Joint Health and Safety Committee, or a health and safety representative. More often than not, this process will likely require an extended involvement in a protracted investigation potentially involving the Ministry of Labour, the Police, and the Coroner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Initiatives</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 15:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/project/</guid>
      <description>Undocumented workers in Ontario are more likely to take physically demanding jobs for less than minimum wage, and are more often exposed to hazards that cause accidents and injuries.
Since early spring, we have participated in numerous demonstrations, cultural events and community fairs, and we have outreached through workshops and presentations.
We are pleased to announce two interactive initiatives that have been created to further connect with the Spanish-speaking community:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trabajadores Indocumentados / Undocumented Workers</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/undocumented-workers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 11:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/undocumented-workers/</guid>
      <description>Projecto de Ayuda a Trabajadores Indocumentados con Problemas de Salud y Seguridad en el Trabajo Preventing Injuries amongst Undocumented Workers Click here to access the English version of this web page.
Click the below links to access for our booklets in English and Spanish:
WORKERS&amp;rsquo; GUIDE TO OCCUPATIONAL HEALTH AND SAFETY TU SALUD Y SEGURIDAD EN EL TRABAJO: Información para Trabajadores  Todos y todas necesitamos protección en el trabajo independientemente de nuestro estatus en Canadá.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newsletters</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/newsletters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 15:43:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/newsletters/</guid>
      <description>The Workers&amp;rsquo; Health and Safety Legal Clinic&amp;rsquo;s newsletters feature commentary on case law and legislative reform, highlight ongoing clinic activities, special projects as well as recent workplace health and safety news.
Scroll down to access the Clinic&amp;rsquo;s newsletters dating back to 2010.
Spring 2017 - Issue: Vol. 25, No. 1
IN THIS ISSUE &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; Case Report: All Parties are Equal before the Human Rights Tribunal / Law Reform – Workers’ Rights in Focus: The Changing Workplaces Review / Clinic Update – New Website Launch: www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Law Reform</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/law-reform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 20:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/law-reform/</guid>
      <description>The Workers’ Health and Safety Legal Clinic (WHSLC) participates in law reform and community development activities that benefit or assist low wage non-unionized workers in Ontario.
Law reform is an important component to WHSLC activities. We engage in networking with like-minded organizations, and we participate in a variety of law reform and community development initiatives that seek to make systematic changes to the laws and policies governing employment, health and safety, workers&amp;rsquo; compensation and related workplace laws.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archives</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 20:05:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/archives/</guid>
      <description>The following archives include a diverse collection of Clinic newsletters, print materials, Annual Reports and other historical documentation.
 Please note: Some of the archived Clinic newsletters contain within them links to documents that may no longer be available. To inquire further, contact us.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outreach</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/public-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 16:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/public-education/</guid>
      <description>Public Legal Education The Workers&amp;rsquo; Health and Safety Legal Clinic (WHSLC) has developed a strong focus on public legal education by way of oral presentations and workshops to community agencies, schools, job connection programs, apprenticeship programs and employment readiness programs such as Enhanced Language Training.
Our Community Legal Workers travel all over the City of Toronto and the Greater Toronto Area to inform youth, job seekers and newcomers about employment rights as well as health and safety rights at work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legal Services</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/legal-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 14:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/legal-services/</guid>
      <description>What We Do The Workers&amp;rsquo; Health and Safety Legal Clinic (WHSLC) provides legal services to low-income non-unionized workers who need assistance with legal matters that relate to their employment rights or their health and safety rights at work. Our legal services include summary legal advice, brief legal services, referrals, and legal representation.
Your privacy is very important to us. The WHSLC follows the Law Society of Upper Canada&amp;rsquo;s rules regarding client confidentiality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canada Labour Code</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/dismissals/canada-labor-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/dismissals/canada-labor-code/</guid>
      <description>Unjust Dismissals We represent workers who were employed in federally regulated workplaces (such as banks, telecommunications, inter-provincial transportation) and dismissed in a manner that does not comply with the Canada Labour Code (CLC). The CLC contains unjust dismissal provisions that apply to non-managerial workers employed for 12 months (1 year) or more who are dismissed without just cause. We also represent workers in federally regulated workplaces that have been punished or fired for raising an occupational health and safety issue or concern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employment Standards</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/dismissals/employment-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/dismissals/employment-standards/</guid>
      <description>Reprisals It is against the law for an employer or agency to punish or terminate workers for enforcing or trying to enforce the rights found under the Employment Standards Act (ESA). These rights include the right to receive minimum wage, overtime pay, pay stubs, sick leave, parental leave, termination pay, vacation pay, and much more.
WHSLC lawyers are available to appear at the Ontario Labour Relations Board to represent workers who have been disciplined/fired for exercising or trying to exercise their rights under the ESA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health and Safety Reprisals</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/dismissals/hsreprisals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/dismissals/hsreprisals/</guid>
      <description>The core of our Clinic&amp;rsquo;s mandate is to represent workers who are disciplined or fired for raising health and safety concerns at work. Some common health and safety concerns are unsafe working conditions, workplace harassment, workplace violence, poor ventilation or exposure to chemical hazards. These are just a few of the health and safety concerns that can arise in any workplace.
WHSLC lawyers are experienced in advocacy before the Ontario Labour Relations Board and in seeking remedies such as lost wages, general damages, and reinstatement to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Rights Applications</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/dismissals/human-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/dismissals/human-rights/</guid>
      <description>Employment and Disability We represent workers who are dismissed from work because of a disability or because they asked for accommodation or a change in work duties due to a disability. We have acted for workers who lose their jobs simply for having an injury at work for which Workplace Safety and Insurance Board (WSIB) benefits were claimed.
 Go back </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Claims Court</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/dismissals/small-claims/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/dismissals/small-claims/</guid>
      <description>Wrongful Dismissal and Constructive Dismissal Lawsuits We file lawsuits against employers and represent workers who are wrongfully dismissed or laid off without proper notice or pay in lieu (instead) of notice.
Additionally, if there is a fundamental change to working conditions that leave a worker with no option but to quit, we can represent workers in a lawsuit against the employer based on constructive dismissal.
 Go back </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlawful Dismissals</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/unlawful-dismissals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/unlawful-dismissals/</guid>
      <description>The Workers&amp;rsquo; Health and Safety Legal Clinic provides advice and representation on a number of unlawful dismissal matters including:
 Health and Safety Reprisals Employment Standards: Reprisals and Termination Pay/Severance Pay Claims Human Rights Applications Canada Labour Code: Unjust Dismissals and Reprisals Small Claims Court: Wrongful Dismissal and Constructive Dismissal Lawsuits   Go back </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workplace Safety and Insurance Board</title>
      <link>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/workplace-safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pemazomkyi.com/features/services/workplace-safety/</guid>
      <description>Workers covered by Workplace Safety and Insurance Act have the right to claim benefits from the Workplace Safety and Insurance Board (WSIB). Benefits can include loss of earnings benefits (also known as workers’ compensation) or healthcare coverage. The WSIB also assists with return to work and retraining. We provide advice for all WSIB issues but representation only in specific types of claim issues like Work Transition Services appeals as well as Occupational Disease appeals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>