<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hazards on My Blog Site</title>
    <link>/tags/hazards/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hazards on My Blog Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 08:04:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/hazards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual Report 2017</title>
      <link>/communications/annual-report-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 08:04:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/communications/annual-report-2017/</guid>
      <description>The Workers&amp;rsquo; Health and Safety Legal Clinic’s Annual Report outlines the activities and initiatives that were made in pursuit of advocating for workers’ rights. It further details the Clinic’s efforts to continue providing consistently high quality services in a cost-effective, efficient and innovative manner. The Clinic provides such legal services as advice, representation, public legal education and law reform concerning occupational health and safety and related workplace laws.
 The following PDF documents are available for review -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Summer 2017 Newsletter – Vol. 25, No. 2</title>
      <link>/communications/-summer-2017-newsletter-vol.-25-no.-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/communications/-summer-2017-newsletter-vol.-25-no.-2/</guid>
      <description>The Workers’ Health and Safety Legal Clinic is pleased to publish its Summer 2017 Newsletter – Vol. 25, No. 2.
In this publication, you will find commentary about clinic casework and law reform efforts, as well as meet our new staff.
 Read more on these issues in the Summer 2017 Clinic Newsletter.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radon Hazards</title>
      <link>/communications/newsletter-2016-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 20:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/communications/newsletter-2016-08/</guid>
      <description>U of T Engineering Students’ proposal for Ontario Building Code changes for Radon Gas. According to the World Health Organization, radon gas has become the second leading cause of lung cancer. In Ontario, high levels of radon can be found within Toronto’s GTA. Since there are no legal requirements in Ontario for radon testing, the currentOntario Building Code is inadequate to handle radon as a rising problem.The Canadian Environmental Law Association issued a report in November 2014 called Radon in Homes, Schools, and Workplaces: CELA Finds Legal Protections Lacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operation Rainbow</title>
      <link>/communications/operation-rainbow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 21:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/communications/operation-rainbow/</guid>
      <description>U of T Engineering Students’ proposals to safely replace the dangerous high school Rainbow Experiment. Our Clinic continued its partnership with first year engineering students at the University of Toronto participating in U of T Engineering Strategies &amp;amp; Practice Course, and the Multidisciplinary Capstone Design Course.Proposed by Clinic volunteer, Dr. Michael Grossman, “Operation Rainbow” is a project that seeks to resolve the safety problems surrounding the Rainbow Experiment: a laboratory experiment performed in secondary schools that identify characteristic colours produced by crystalline compounds when ignited.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>