<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wsib on My Blog Site</title>
    <link>/tags/wsib/</link>
    <description>Recent content in wsib on My Blog Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 15:00:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/wsib/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Workers&#39; Comp Is A Right! - December 10, 2018 at 11:30am</title>
      <link>/communications/workers-comp-is-a-right-december-10-2018-at-11-30am/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 15:00:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/communications/workers-comp-is-a-right-december-10-2018-at-11-30am/</guid>
      <description>Workers’ Comp is a Right! Join us for a province-wide week of action from December 10th to the 14th, and take a stand for fairness for injured workers!
 In Toronto, we’re kicking the week off with a rally on Monday, December 10th at 11:30am outside the Ministry of Labour located at 400 University Avenue - view map for directions.
Click here to access a PDF of the 2018 Toronto Rally Poster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workers&#39; Guide</title>
      <link>/communications/workers-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 10:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/communications/workers-guide/</guid>
      <description>Protect your health and safety! As a worker in Ontario, you have basic health and safety rights. It is against the law for your boss to fire you or punish you (or threaten to fire or punish you) for using your health and safety rights.
 Click below to learn more:
WORKERS’ GUIDE TO OCCUPATIONAL HEALTH AND SAFETY.  For more information on our services or if you have have been fired or punished for speaking out about your rights, contact us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injured Workers&#39; Demonstration - December 11, 2017 at 11:30am</title>
      <link>/communications/injured-workers-demonstration-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 09:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/communications/injured-workers-demonstration-1/</guid>
      <description>All We Want for Christmas is Fair Workers’ Comp! Injured Workers&amp;rsquo; Holiday Outreach Blitz.  Toronto:
Meet at 11:30am at Yonge &amp;amp; Dundas Square [Map]
Contact workerscompisaright@gmail.com for more information or visit the Facebook event page.
 On Monday December 11th, join us in communities across the province, to celebrate the strength and resilience of injured workers who refuse to back down from the struggle for fair compensation.
The holiday season can be a difficult time for injured workers who have been forced into poverty because of the Workplace Safety and Insurance Board&amp;rsquo;s focus on saving its own money by slashing compensation benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injured Workers’ Day - June 1st, 2017 at 11:30am, Queen’s Park</title>
      <link>/communications/injured-workers-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 12:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/communications/injured-workers-day/</guid>
      <description>Workers&amp;rsquo; Compensation is a Right! Injured Workers&amp;rsquo; Day Rally and March. Despite the epidemic of precarious, unsafe, and toxic work, the Workplace Safety and Insurance Board (WSIB) is more concerned with its own bottom line than with protecting the well-being of injured workers in Ontario.
We need to come together and demand our right to workers&amp;rsquo; compensation.
Join us on the streets!
June 1st , 2017 &amp;mdash; 11:30am - at Queen’s Park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injured Workers&#39; Demonstration</title>
      <link>/communications/injured-workers-demonstration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 09:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/communications/injured-workers-demonstration/</guid>
      <description>Injured workers, advocates, union members and allies rallied in Toronto on December 12th, for the annual call to action against austerity measures that have been taken by the Workers Safety and Insurance Board (WSIB).
  The rally began at the WSIB’s Toronto office located at 200 Front Street West and then continued at the Ombudsman’s office located at 483 Bay Street. A letter voicing concerns with the WSIB was delivered to a representative of Ontario’s Ombudsman, Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>